Adam Humphrey

2408 Leon Street Apt. 101, Austin, Texas
Phone: (512) 663-1160
E-mail: Adamthumph@gmail.com
Website: adamhumphrey.github.io
GitHub: https://github.com/AdamHumphrey/

Objective

To find a journalism job or internship where I can combine my passion for reporting, writing, coding and data visualization.

Summary

I've worked for a variety of publications ranging from the school newspaper to lifestyle magazines and tech trade magazines. I am studying computer science in addition to journalism, and can write clean code as well as strong stories. I work well under pressure, can think on my feet and strive to meet every deadline.

Experience

Senior Tech Staff, The Daily Texan

Austin, Texas — September 2015 to Present

As part of the tech department I work on a team that creates interactive elements for stories published on the web and work on miscellaneous projects with each department in the paper.

Digital Intern, Austin Monthly

Austin, Texas — May 2015 to August 2015

My main responsibility was to research and create content for the city magazine's website. I wrote about a wide variety of topics, many times on a strict deadline. I constantly searched for article ideas and maintained other features on the website.

Student Intern, NewBay Media

Austin, Texas — January 2015 to August 2015

I copy edited stories and press releases that were sent to be published on the AV Network website. I also wrote several original feature pieces for AV Network's website.

Editorial Intern, The Alcalde

Austin, Texas — August 2014 to December 2014

I researched, pitched, and wrote stories for the bimonthly UT alumni magazine. I also created content for the magazine's website, and proof read material that appeared in the print edition of the magazine.

Education

University of Texas at Austin

Majoring in Journalism — 2012 to Present (Graduation date: May 2016)

I'm majoring in journalism while also attempting a certificate in computer science and maintaining a 3.56 GPA. I am tailoring my courses to focus on data journalism and coding so I can be better prepared to create compelling, interactive and data-driven content for print and the web.

Skills

- Data mapping and visualization using ArcGIS and Adobe Illustrator
- Python, Java, HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript coding language experience
- Create, clean, and manage databases of information
- Strong writer with background writing on a wide variety of topics

Activities

Phi Kappa Tau Vice President of Operations